Export of name directive not found.
You may encounter this error when you reference a directive
in a template that has not been defined, not properly imported,
or when it's export name has not been declared.
Let's take a look at a simple reproduction and solution.
Then we'll take a closer look at ngModules to gain a deeper
understanding of this issue, we can start debugging by finding
the error in the browser console or in the terminal from the Angular compiler output.
In either case, it will take you to the template that references
the nonexistent directive and notice how the IDE is catching this error in advance.
Once there rule out a simple typo as the cause of the error.
A more likely cause is that the ngModule that exports that directive has not been imported yet.
In this example, we're referencing ngForm, which is exported by Angular's Forms module.
Therefore, we can address the problem by going into the app
module and adding the Forms module to the imports array.
Save the file, then notice how the warning in the component template has disappeared.
That's because Angular has no way to know about that directive until it's been imported in the ngModule.
If nothing changes, first, try restarting your local Dev server.
If the issue remains double check that you're importing the proper ngModule.
For example, we can search the directive name in the official Angular documentation.
The documentation for that directive will tell us exactly which ngModule to import.
Now, it's also worth noting that you may run into this error
when you attempt to assign one of your own custom directives to a template variable.
Let's take a look at a component and directive that both live within the same ngModule.
The directive has a selector of app form.
However, if we attempt to assign that directive to a template variable,
it gives us a warning that there is no directive with export as set to App form.
In order to use a directive as a template variable, we need
to define a name in the export as option in the directive decorator,
and once the export name has been defined, the error goes away.
The key takeaway here is that when using a directive as a
template variable, it must have an export name within the directive decorator.
Now that we know how to debug this error, let's take a closer
look at ngModules and directives to understand why it happens in the first place.
When you create an ngModule on Angular, you declare components
and director electives that are to be used privately within this module.
But in many cases you have components and directives defined here that should be used outside of this module.
You can make these classes public by adding them to the exports array.
That's how you share components and directives between ngModules.
But keep in mind that when working with Directives, you also
need to consider how they'll be consumed in the template.
For example, here, we have a directive with a class name of ngForm.
If the goal is to use the directive as a property or attribute on an element,
We define a selector as in a CSS selector
like a class name or attribute, then the directive is instantiated
when that selector is encountered in the template.
However, if the goal is to use the directive as a template variable, that same mechanism doesn't work.
Therefore, we set an export as name to make that name known
to Angular, allowing it to instantiate the directive in a template variable.
Let's go ahead and recap when you encounter the export of name directive not found.
Error debug it by finding the template that references the directive.
Then determine which ngModule needs to be imported.
Once the module has been identified, it can be imported in your own local ngModule.
If the issue is not related to an ngModule, import verified
that the directive has an export as property set when used in the context of a template variable.
For additional examples and details, reference the official Angular documentation.